A Finding Aid to the Morris Louis and Morris Louis Estate papers, circa 1910s-2007, bulk 1965-2000, in the Archives of American Art AAA.louimorr
Archives of American Art
- Morris Louis Estate Papers, bulk 1965-2000; 1947-2007; Series 2; 14.9 Linear feet Boxes 3-19, OV 20
  - Gallery Records, 1947-2002; 2.1
    - National Gallery of Art, 1975-1983 (Box 6, Folder 35-39)
    - Milwaukee Art Museum, National Symposium of Art Museum Docents, 1983 (Box 6, Folder 40)
    - Paul Kasmin Gallery, 2001 (Box 6, Folder 41)
    - Riva Yares Gallery, 2001 (Box 6, Folder 42-43)
    - Stadtische Kunsthalle, Dusseldorf, 1974 (Box 7, Folder 1-2)
    - Tate Gallery, 1979-1986 (Box 7, Folder 3)
    - Tel Aviv Museum, 1972-1988 (Box 7, Folder 4-6)
    - University of Maryland Art Gallery, Baltimore, Maryland, 1971-1974 (Box 7, Folder 7)
    - Waddington Galleries, 1968-1980 (Box 7, Folder 8-9)
    - Walker Art Center, Minneapolis, 1976-1981 (Box 7, Folder 10-11)
    - Whitney Museum of American Art, 1969-circa 1978 (Box 7, Folder 12)
    - Westfalisches Landesmuseum (Westphalian State Museum of Art and Cultural History, Munster, Germany), 1996-1997 (Box 7, Folder 13)
    - Oversized Andre Emmerich Gallery, removed from Box 5, Folder 3, 1985 (Box 19, Folder 1)
    - Oversized Bezalel Academy of Art & Design, Morris Louis Gallery, removed from Box 5, Folder 28, 1987-1991 (Box 19, Folder 2)
    - Oversized Museum of Modern Art, Shiga, Japan, removed from Box 6, Folder 33, 1986 (Box 19, Folder 3)
    - Oversized Israel Museum, removed from Box 6, Folder 14, circa 1985 (Box OV 20)
    - Oversized Staditsche Kunsthalle, Dusseldorf, removed from Box 7, Folder 2, 1974 (Box OV 20)
  - Art Records and Inventories, 1960-1992; 2.2
    Inventory cards were maintained according to their original order. The cards sometimes include several numerical references, including original Morris Louis numbers (referred to as ML #), Santini numbers (of the Santini Brothers Warehouse), and "DU" numbers. It is not clear what "DU" stands for. Some cards have a color tab attached, while others have minimal description containing perhaps only a title and date. At the time of the Louis' death, numerous unidentified paintings were stored in rolls, and, thus, a numbering system was assigned posthumously. These numbers are most likely the DU numbers.
    Inventory files are arranged in numerical order according to "DU" number, though notations within files may refer to additional filing numbers. Inventory files are connected to inventory notecards, though some files exist where notecards are absent. Some files contain photocopies of relevant inventory notecard, as well.
    In both inventory cards and inventory files, systems were used over the course of 30 years, which accounts for varying numbers assigned, descriptions, and notations in multiple handwritings.
    One inventory file is dedicated to researching the whereabouts of a missing painting identified as 5-71 "a large veil on a triple-fold stretcher."
    Art inventory files and cards contain extensive details about Louis' artwork and often include photographs and transparencies, as well as written descriptions. The files contain documentation of the movement of artwork, whether showing in an exhibition, donated to a museum or gallery, or sold through auction or to a private collector. There are also notations about artwork donations made my Marcella Brenner before her death. Additionally, several estate inventories and lists of museums where pieces were located are filed here.
    - Inventory Notecards, 1960-1992 (Box 7, Folder 14-25)
    - Inventory Notecards, 1987-1992 (Box 8, Folder 1-3)
    - Inventory Files, Nos. [1]-[18], 1960-1992 (Box 8, Folder 4)
    - Inventory Files, Nos. [19]-[35], 1960-1992 (Box 8, Folder 5)
    - Inventory Files, Nos. [36]-[50], 1960-1992 (Box 8, Folder 6)
    - Inventory Files, Nos. [51]-[65], 1960-1992 (Box 8, Folder 7)
    - Inventory Files, Nos. [66]-[77], 1960-1992 (Box 8, Folder 8)
    - Inventory Files, Nos. [78]-[92], 1960-1992 (Box 8, Folder 9)
    - Inventory Files, Nos. [93]-[1-05], 1960-1992 (Box 8, Folder 10)
    - Inventory Files, Nos. [1-06]-[1-16], 1960-1992 (Box 8, Folder 11)
    - Inventory Files, Nos. [1-17]-[1-29], 1960-1992 (Box 8, Folder 12)
    - Inventory Files, Nos. [1-30]-[1-43], 1960-1992 (Box 8, Folder 13)
    - Inventory Files, Nos. [1-45]-[1-55], 1960-1992 (Box 8, Folder 14)
    - Inventory Files, Nos. [1-56]-[1-72], 1960-1992 (Box 8, Folder 15)
    - Inventory Files, Nos. [1-73]-[1-89], 1960-1992 (Box 8, Folder 16)
    - Inventory Files, Nos. [1-90]-[2-06], 1960-1992 (Box 8, Folder 17)
    - Inventory Files, Nos. [2-07]-[2-22], 1960-1992 (Box 9, Folder 1)
    - Inventory Files, Nos. [2-23]-[2-35], 1960-1992 (Box 9, Folder 2)
    - Inventory Files, Nos. [2-36]-[2-47], 1960-1992 (Box 9, Folder 3)
    - Inventory Files, Nos. [2-48]-[2-58], 1960-1992 (Box 9, Folder 4)
    - Inventory Files, Nos. [2-59]-[2-74], 1960-1992 (Box 9, Folder 5)
    - Inventory Files, Nos. [2-76]-[2-86], 1960-1992 (Box 9, Folder 6)
    - Inventory Files, Nos. [2-87]-[2-99], 1960-1992 (Box 9, Folder 7)
    - Inventory Files, Nos. [3-00]-[3-12], 1960-1992 (Box 9, Folder 8)
    - Inventory Files, Nos. [3-13]-[3-23], 1960-1992 (Box 9, Folder 9)
    - Inventory Files, Nos. [3-24]-[3-36], 1960-1992 (Box 9, Folder 10)
    - Inventory Files, Nos. [3-37]-[3-51], 1960-1992 (Box 9, Folder 11)
    - Inventory Files, Nos. [3-52]-[3-66], 1960-1992 (Box 9, Folder 12)
    - Inventory Files, Nos. [3-67]-[3-81], 1960-1992 (Box 9, Folder 13)
    - Inventory Files, Nos. [3-82]-[3-92], 1960-1992 (Box 9, Folder 14)
    - Inventory Files, Nos. [3-93]-[4-10], 1960-1992 (Box 9, Folder 15)
    - Inventory Files, Nos. [4-11]-[4-28], 1960-1992 (Box 10, Folder 1)
    - Inventory Files, Nos. [4-29]-[4-43], 1960-1992 (Box 10, Folder 2)
    - Inventory Files, Nos. [4-44]-[4-56], 1960-1992 (Box 10, Folder 3)
    - Inventory Files, Nos. [4-57]-[4-70], 1960-1992 (Box 10, Folder 4)
    - Inventory Files, Nos. [4-71]-[4-90], 1960-1992 (Box 10, Folder 5)
    - Inventory Files, Nos. [4-92]-[5-06], 1960-1992 (Box 10, Folder 6)
    - Inventory Files, Nos. [5-07]-[5-26], 1960-1992 (Box 10, Folder 7)
    - Inventory Files, Nos. [5-27]-[5-39], 1960-1992 (Box 10, Folder 8)
    - Inventory Files, Nos. [5-40]-[5-69], 1960-1992 (Box 10, Folder 9)
    - Inventory Files, Nos. [5-71] Missing Painting, 1960-1992 (Box 10, Folder 10)
    - Inventory Files, Nos. [5-72]-[5-81], 1960-1992 (Box 10, Folder 11)
    - Inventory Files, Titles Only, A-Z, 1960-1992 (Box 10, Folder 12)
    - Estate Inventory Lists, 1985-1987 (Box 10, Folder 13)
    - International Museums, Inventory List, circa 1986 (Box 10, Folder 14)
    - National & International Museums, Visual Inventory, circa 1986 (Box 10, Folder 15)
    - Estate Inventory of Morris Louis Drawings, 1988 (Box 10, Folder 16)
    - Estate Inventory of Morris Louis Drawings, 1988 (Box 11, Folder 1-3)
  - Legal Records, 1962-1989; 2.3
    Legal records contain documentation of the Bernstein v. Brenner lawsuit and trial, including trial notes and preparation notes; correspondence between I.S. Weissbrodt as the Morris Louis Estate lawyer and relevant parties; copies of the settlement contract from the trial; and a court-mandated inventory of the Louis Estate artwork holdings and subsequent records of whereabouts, sales, and transfers.
    Correspondence with I.S. Weissbrodt spans 25 years and includes notes to and from Marcella Brenner regarding sale of Morris Louis artwork, issues as they arose, gallery contracts and agreements, deeds of gift records, and other legal documents.
    Documentation of the Bernstein v. Brenner lawsuit is incomplete.
    - Correspondence, Answer to 'Show Cause', 1970 (Box 11, Folder 4)
    - Correspondence, Pre-1954 Paintings, Previously Unknown Works, 1964-1986 (Box 11, Folder 5)
    - Correspondence, I. S. Weissbrodt, 1965-1989 (Box 11, Folder 6-31)
    - Court-Ruled Paintings Inventory & History of Sales, Notes & Lists Summary, 1964 (Box 11, Folder 32)
    - Court-Ruled Paintings Inventory & History of Sales, 1962-1968 (Box 11, Folder 33)
    - Louis Paintings, Locations, 1987-1989 (Box 11, Folder 34)
    - Settlement Contract, Bernstein v. Brenner, 1970 (Box 11, Folder 35)
    - Trial Notes, Bernstein v. Brenner, 1970 (Box 11, Folder 36)
  - Financial Records, 1959-1998; 2.4
    Financial records consist of extensive sales records for Morris Louis artwork between 1959 and 1989. Also included are bonds, tax records and returns documenting inheritance and estate taxes, a single statement documenting the sale of a Louis painting, and documentation of the P.E.F. Israel Endowment Fund, a fund for innovative teaching set up and sponsored by Marcella Brenner, 1971-2007, via the Morris Louis Estate.
    - Bonds, 1974-1998 (Box 11, Folder 37)
    - P.E.F. Israel Endowment Fund, 1986-1989 (Box 11, Folder 38-40)
    - Sales Records for Louis Paintings, 1959-1966 (Box 11, Folder 41)
    - Sales Records for Louis Paintings, 1969-1989 (Box 12, Folder 1-3)
    - Statement of Morris Louis Painting Sale, 1996 (Box 12, Folder 4)
    - Taxes, D.C. Estate Tax, 1962-1964 (Box 12, Folder 5)
    - Taxes, Estate Tax, 1962-1965 (Box 12, Folder 6)
    - Taxes, Federal & D.C. Estate Tax, Inheritance Tax, 1962-1963 (Box 12, Folder 7)
    - Taxes, 1962-1964 (Box 12, Folder 8-9)
  - Printed Material, 1960-2006; 2.5
    Printed material includes brochures and notecards, blank wall and desk calendars containing representative images of Morris Louis paintings, extensive clippings, magazines, sales catalogs, and journals, exhibition catalogs, exhibition notecards and event announcements.
    Other publications include gallery and museum reports and miscellaneous publications containing depictions of Morris Louis' paintings and references, and a medical report of the U.S. Department of Health with Louis' Beta-Kappa as the cover image.
    - Brochures & Notecards, 1989-2002 (Box 12, Folder 10-11)
    - Calendars, 1995-2003 (Box 12, Folder 12)
      Oversize material housed in Box 19, Folder 4.
    - Clippings, 1966-1991 (Box 12, Folder 13-30)
    - Clippings, 1992-2006 (Box 13, Folder 1-14)
    - Exhibition Catalogs, 1965-1988 (Box 13, Folder 15-34)
    - Exhibition Catalogs, 1989-2006 (Box 14, Folder 1-9)
    - Exhibition Events & Announcements, 1965-2000 (Box 14, Folder 10)
    - Notecards Featuring Louis Paintings, circa 1960s-circa 1980s (Box 14, Folder 11)
    - Other Publications, 1968-1997 (Box 14, Folder 12-19)
    - Oversized Calendars, removed from Box 12, Folder 13, 1984-1998 (Box 19, Folder 4)
    - Oversized Clippings, 1971-2007 (Box 19, Folder 5-10)
  - Writings, 1963-1988; 2.6
    Writings include typescripts, essay drafts, and notes about Morris Louis, as well as documentation and manuscript copies of the book, Trustee for the Human Race: Litigation over the Morris Louis Paintings written by Ruth S. Blau, and contracted by Marcella Brenner.
    - Typescript, Sybil Myersburg "Morris Louis: A Memoir", 1963 (Box 14, Folder 20)
    - Typescript, Dan Robbins "Morris Louis", 1963 (Box 14, Folder 21)
    - Notes, 1966-1988 (Box 14, Folder 22)
    - Essay Drafts, Helen Jacobson "As I Remember Morris Louis", 1970 (Box 14, Folder 23)
    - Typescript, Doris Margaret Thornton "Morris Louis: A Painter, Recollected in Tranquility", circa 1972 (Box 14, Folder 24)
    - Typescript, Article by Karin Alexis, 1977 (Box 14, Folder 25)
    - Book Contract/Agreement, Ruth S. Blau for Trustee for the Human Race: Litigation Over the Morris Louis Paintings, 1988 (Box 14, Folder 26)
    - Manuscript, Ruth S. Blau, Trustee for the Human Race: Litigation Over the Morris Louis Paintings, 1988 (Box 14, Folder 27-28)
  - Photographs, circa 1950s-2001; 2.7
    Photographs consist primarily of gallery installation photographs of Morris Louis paintings and drawings.There are also images of Marcella Brenner and Andre Emmerich; slides of Morris Louis paintings owned by his estate; photographs of unstretched, unrolled Morris Louis paintings housed at the Santini Brothers Warehouse; a photograph of a Morris Louis-like Lichtenstein work, noted as "Roy Lichtenstein's Variation of a Louis 'Unfurled'"; photographs taken at two Morris Louis exhibition openings; and color and black and white transparencies of Morris Louis artwork.
    - Photographs of Marcella Brenner, circa 1950s-1995 (Box 14, Folder 29)
    - Photographs of Marcella Brenner at Lenne School Event, 2001 (Box 14, Folder 30)
    - Photographs of Andre Emmerich in Milan, 1990 March (Box 14, Folder 31)
    - Artwork: Estate Paintings, Slides, circa 1980 (Box 14, Folder 32-33)
    - Artwork: Roy Lichtenstein's Variation of a Louis "Unfurled", 1973 (Box 14, Folder 34)
    - Artwork: Santini Brothers Warehouse Paintings, Slides, 1965 (Box 14, Folder 35)
    - Artwork: Transparencies, circa 1970s (Box 14, Folder 36)
    - Exhibition Opening, "Morris Louis Retrospective," Boston Museum of Fine Arts, 1967 April (Box 15, Folder 1)
    - Exhibition Opening, "Morris Louis," Westphalian State Museum of Art and Cultural History, Munster, Germany, 1986 May (Box 15, Folder 2)
    - Exhibition, "Major Themes & Variations," National Gallery of Art (sign only), 1976 September-1977 January (Box 15, Folder 3)
    - Gallery Installation, Andre Emmerich Gallery, "Unfurleds", 1964 (Box 15, Folder 4)
    - Gallery Installation, Andre Emmerich Gallery, "Veils", 1966 (Box 15, Folder 5)
    - Gallery Installation, Andre Emmerich Gallery, "Paintings of the Spring '62", 1968 (Box 15, Folder 6)
    - Gallery Installation, Andre Emmerich Gallery, "Veils", 1969 (Box 15, Folder 7)
    - Gallery Installation, Andre Emmerich Gallery, "Unfurleds", 1970 (Box 15, Folder 8)
    - Gallery Installation, Andre Emmerich Gallery, "Stripes", 1972 (Box 15, Folder 9)
    - Gallery Installation, Andre Emmerich Gallery, Zurich Exhibition, 1974 (Box 15, Folder 10)
    - Gallery Installation, Andre Emmerich Gallery, "Nine Major Works", 1978 (Box 15, Folder 11)
    - Gallery Installation, Andre Emmerich Gallery, "Solid Columns", 1980 (Box 15, Folder 12)
    - Gallery Installation, Andre Emmerich Gallery, "A Commemorative Exhibition", 1982 (Box 15, Folder 13)
    - Gallery Installation, Andre Emmerich Gallery, "Drawings 1948-1953", 1982 (Box 15, Folder 14)
    - Gallery Installation, Andre Emmerich Gallery, "Drawings", 1985 (Box 15, Folder 15)
    - Gallery Installation, Andre Emmerich Gallery, "Exhibition in Honor of the Catalogue Raisonne", 1985 (Box 15, Folder 16)
    - Gallery Installation, Andre Emmerich Gallery, 1989 (Box 15, Folder 17)
    - Gallery Installation, Andre Emmerich Gallery, "Veils and Variations", 1992 (Box 15, Folder 18)
    - Gallery Installation, Andre Emmerich Gallery, "Variations on a Theme", 1995 (Box 15, Folder 19)
    - Gallery Installation, Asher/Faure Gallery, Los Angeles, 1979 (Box 15, Folder 20)
    - Gallery Installation, Cleveland Museum of Modern Art, 1967 (Box 15, Folder 21)
    - Gallery Installation, Louisiana Museum, Denmark, circa 1970 (Box 15, Folder 22)
    - Gallery Installation, National Museum of Modern Art, Tokyo, circa 1960s (Box 15, Folder 23)
    - Gallery Installation, Riva Yares Gallery, California, 1989 (Box 15, Folder 24)
    - Gallery Installation, Rome - New York Art Foundation, 1960 (Box 15, Folder 25)
    - Gallery Installation, Seattle Art Museum, 1967 (Box 15, Folder 26-27)
    - Gallery Installation, St. Louis Art Museum, "Morris Louis 1912-1962", 1967 (Box 15, Folder 28)
    - Gallery Installation, Tel Aviv Museum, 1981 (Box 15, Folder 29)
    - Gallery Installation, Whitney Museum of American Art, New York, 1995 (Box 15, Folder 30)
    - Gallery Installation, Musee D'Art Moderne, Saint Etienne, 1998 (Box 15, Folder 31)
  - Project Files, 1966-2007; 2.8
    Project files are found for the Morris Louis catalogue raisonne; three film projects by Robert Pierce Productions, including "Morris Louis: Radiant Zones," "Pictures to an Exhibition," and "Morris Louis"; a NET Program, "The New Abstraction: Morris Louis & Kenneth Noland"; a WETA-TV documentary on Morris Louis; a film associated with the "Morris Louis Now" exhibition; and the Anita Faatz interviews of 27 artists talking about Morris Louis.
    - Catalogue Raisonne Project Files, 1966-1986; 2.8.1
      The catalogue raisonne project files contain twenty years of documentation and correspondence relating to the creation of Morris Louis: The Complete Paintings (A Catalogue Raisonne), compiled and written by Diane Upright Headley. Files document interviews, extensive research, and a final exhibition in 1985 at the Andre Emmerich Gallery to honor the completed Morris Louis catalogue raisonne. The publication is not found in the records.
      - Catalogue Raisonne Project Files, 1966-1986 (Box 15, Folder 32-38)
    - Robert Pierce Productions Film Projects, 1975-2001; 2.8.2
      Robert Pierce Productions film projects include documentation and interview transcripts for three film projects: "Morris Louis: Radiant Zones," "Pictures to an Exhibition," and "Morris Louis." No original video or film is found here.
      The "Morris Louis: Radiant Zones" was a 25 minute documentary completed in 1986. Although ultimately produced by Robert Pierce Productions, the film project originally began in 1979 in Australia and was funded by the Australian Film Commission. In 1985 it was agreed that the 16mm print would be transferred and non-theatrically exhibited at the Fort Worth Art Museum in the United States, and curated by Diane Upright Headley.
      - "Morris Louis: Radiant Zones," Project Documentation, 1979-1985 (Box 15, Folder 39)
      - "Morris Louis: Radiant Zones" Project, Interview Transcript, Nick Wilder (Tapes 1-4), circa 1980 (Box 15, Folder 40)
      - "Morris Louis: Radiant Zones" Project, Interview Transcript, James Collins (Tapes 5-7), circa 1980 (Box 15, Folder 41)
      - "Morris Louis: Radiant Zones" Project, Interview Transcript, Andre Emmerich (Tapes 8-11), 1979 (Box 15, Folder 42)
      - "Morris Louis: Radiant Zones" Project, Interview Transcript, Michael Fried (Tapes 12-16), 1979 (Box 15, Folder 43)
      - "Morris Louis: Radiant Zones" Project, Interview Transcript, Rubin Lawrence (Tapes 17-19), circa 1980 (Box 15, Folder 44)
      - "Morris Louis: Radiant Zones" Project, Interview Transcript, Diane Upright Headley (Tape 20), 1979 (Box 15, Folder 45)
      - "Morris Louis: Radiant Zones" Project, Interview Transcript, Joe Helman (Tapes 21-23), circa 1980 (Box 15, Folder 46)
      - "Morris Louis: Radiant Zones" Project, Interview Transcript, John Elderfield (Tapes 24-29), 1979 (Box 15, Folder 47)
      - "Morris Louis: Radiant Zones" Project, Interview Transcript, Leonard Bocour (Tapes 30-33), 1979 (Box 15, Folder 48)
      - "Morris Louis: Radiant Zones" Project, Interview Transcript, Charles Schucker (Tapes 34-36), circa 1980 (Box 15, Folder 49)
      - "Morris Louis: Radiant Zones" Project, Interview Transcript, Andre Emmerich (Tape 39), circa 1980 (Box 15, Folder 50)
      - "Morris Louis: Radiant Zones" Project, Interview Transcript, Andre Emmerich & James Lebron (Tapes 40-43), circa 1980 (Box 15, Folder 51)
      - "Morris Louis: Radiant Zones" Project, Interview Transcript, Gifford & Joann Phillips (Tapes 44-47), circa 1980 (Box 15, Folder 52)
      - "Morris Louis: Radiant Zones" Project, Interview Transcript, Helen Frankenthaler (Tape 48), circa 1980 (Box 16, Folder 1)
      - "Morris Louis: Radiant Zones" Project, Interview Transcript, Kenworth Moffet (Tapes 49-51), circa 1980 (Box 16, Folder 2)
      - "Morris Louis: Radiant Zones" Project, Interview Transcript, Anne Truitt (Tapes 52-56), circa 1980-1987 (Box 16, Folder 3)
      - "Morris Louis: Radiant Zones" Project, Interview Transcript, Marcella Brenner (Tapes 57-58), circa 1980 (Box 16, Folder 4)
      - "Pictures to an Exhibition" Project Documentation, 1988-1991 (Box 16, Folder 5)
      - "Morris Louis" Project, Interview Transcript, Marcella Brenner, 2001 (Box 16, Folder 6)
      - "Morris Louis" Project, Interview Transcript, Pat Lipsky, 2001 (Box 16, Folder 7)
      - "Morris Louis" Project, Interview Transcript, Dennis Yares, 2001 (Box 16, Folder 8)
      - "Morris Louis" Project, Interview Transcript, Liz Quisgard, 2001 (Box 16, Folder 9)
      - "Morris Louis" Project, Interview Transcript, Sybil Meyersburg, 2001 (Box 16, Folder 10)
      - "Morris Louis" Project, Interview Transcript, Andre Emmerich, 2001 (Box 16, Folder 11)
      - "Morris Louis" Project, Interview Transcript, Cornelia Noland Reis, 2001 (Box 16, Folder 12)
    - NET Program, "The New Abstraction: Morris Louis & Kenneth Noland", 1966; 2.8.3
      - Interview Transcript, Marcella Brenner, 1966 (Box 16, Folder 13)
      - Interview/Program Transcript, Clement Greenberg, Marcella Brenner, Helen Jacobson, Helen Frankenthaler, and Kenneth Noland, 1966 (Box 16, Folder 14)
      - Interview Transcript, Helen Jacobson, 1966 (Box 16, Folder 15)
    - WETA-TV Documentary on Morris Louis, 1986; 2.8.4
      - Interview Transcript, Marcella Brenner, 1986 (Box 16, Folder 16)
    - Film project, "Morris Louis Now", 2007; 2.8.5
      Found here are the video cassettes for the never fully realized film "Morris Louis Now." The film was produced and directed by Mark Muheim, Muheim Motion Pictures, for Marcella Brenner in 2007. Footage was captured at the High Museum of Art and the Hirshhorn Museum and Sculpture Garden.
      - "Morris Louis Now," Hirshhorn Museum, 2007; 3 Videocassettes (BetacamSP) Duplicates of HDCAM; 3 Videocassettes (HDCAM) (Box 16, Folder 17)
      - "Morris Louis Now," High Museum, 2007; 2 Videocassettes (BetacamSP) Duplicates of HDCAM; 1 Videocassettes (HDCAM) (Box 16, Folder 21)
    - Anita Faatz Interviews, 1970-1976; 2.8.6
      Between 1970-1971 Anita Faatz interviewed 27 artists for a project requested and initiated by Marcella Brenner in 1969. The purpose was to capture recollections and memories of Morris Louis by those who knew him before too much time had passed after his death. The Anita Faatz interview files include project documentation, correspondence, and interviews with 27 individuals on 23 sound cassettes. Most interviews include transcripts.
      Of note are interviews with Clement Greenberg, Helen Frankenthaler, Kenneth Noland, Marcella Brenner, Andre Emmerich, Lawrence and William Rubin, and others.
      - Project Documentation, 1971 (Box 17, Folder 1)
      - Correspondence, 1974-1976 (Box 17, Folder 2)
      - Sophia Bloom Interview, 1971; 2 Sound cassettes No transcript included. (Box 17, Folder 3)
      - Stanley A. Blumberg Interview, 1970; 1 Sound cassettes No transcript included. (Box 17, Folder 4)
      - Leonard Bocour and Clement Greenberg Interviews, 1970; 1 Sound cassettes Includes transcript. (Box 17, Folder 5-6)
      - Marcella and Abner Brenner Interviews, 1971; 1 Sound cassettes Includes transcript. (Box 17, Folder 7-8)
      - Betty Carter Interview (transcript), 1970 (Box 17, Folder 9)
        For sound recording, see Betty Schach Interview, Box 18, Folder 4
      - Andre Emmerich Interview, 1970; 1 Sound cassettes Includes transcript. (Box 17, Folder 10-11)
      - Freda Friedman Interview, 1971; 1 Sound cassettes Includes transcript. (Box 17, Folder 12-13)
      - Clement Greenberg Interview, 1970; 1 Sound cassettes Includes transcript. (Box 17, Folder 14-15)
      - Helen Frankenthaler Interview, 1970; 1 Sound cassettes Includes transcript. (Box 17, Folder 16-17)
      - Helen Jacobson Interview, 1970; 1 Sound cassettes Includes transcript. (Box 17, Folder 18-19)
      - Miriam Jaegerman Interview, 1970; 1 Sound cassettes No transcript included. (Box 17, Folder 20)
      - Jeanette Kear and Annie Siegel Interviews, 1970; 2 Sound cassettes Includes transcript (Jeanette Kear). (Box 17, Folder 21-22)
        For Annie Siegel interview transcript, see Box 18, Folder 11